How often do you find the right person?
Once is a drama, music, romance film directed by John Carney.
A vacuum repairman moonlights as a street musician and hopes for his big break.
One day a Czech immigrant, who earns a living selling flowers, approaches him
with the news that she is also an aspiring singer-songwriter.
The pair decide to collaborate, and the songs that they
compose reflect the story of their blossoming love.
Guy, played by Glen Hansard.
Girl, played by Markéta Irglová.
Timmy Drummer, played by Hugh Walsh.
Lead Guitarist, played by Gerard Hendrick.
Bassist, played by Alaistair Foley.
Eamon, played by Geoff Minogue.
Once is a 2007 Irish
romantic musical drama film
written and directed by John Carney.
The film stars Glen Hansard and Markéta Irglová as two
struggling musicians in Dublin, Ireland.
Hansard and Irglová had previously performed music as the Swell Season,
and composed and performed the film's original songs.
Once spent years in development with the Irish Film Board
and was made for a budget of €112,000.
It was a commercial success, earning substantial per-screen box office
averages in the United States, and received acclaim from critics.
It received awards including the 2007 Independent
Spirit Award for Best Foreign Film.
Hansard and Irglová's song "Falling Slowly" won the 2008 Academy Award for Best Original Song (making Irglova the youngest
person to win an Oscar in a non-acting category), and the soundtrack received a Grammy Award nomination.
The film has also been adapted into a successful stage musical.
The film explores themes of rock 'n' roll,
lovesickness, love of one's life, composer, pop.
The tone is emotional.